<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>3 on Landfried</title>
    <link>https://glandfried.github.io/publication_types/3/</link>
    <description>Recent content in 3 on Landfried</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://glandfried.github.io/publication_types/3/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>TrueSkill Through Time. The full scientific documentation</title>
      <link>https://glandfried.github.io/publication/landfried2021-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glandfried.github.io/publication/landfried2021-learning/</guid>
      <description>Most estimators implemented for the video game industry cannot obtain reliable initial estimates nor guarantee comparability between distant estimates. TrueSkill Through Time solves all these problems by modeling the entire history of activities using a single Bayesian network. This algorithm requires a few iterations to converge, allowing millions of observations to be analyzed using any low-end computer.
To support the use of reliable learning estimators, we provide the first implementations of TrueSkill Through Time for Julia, Python and R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TrueSkill Through Time. The Julia, Python and R packages</title>
      <link>https://glandfried.github.io/publication/landfried2020-ttt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glandfried.github.io/publication/landfried2020-ttt/</guid>
      <description>Packages:
 Julia Package: https://github.com/glandfried/TrueSkillThroughTime.jl Python Package: https://github.com/glandfried/TrueSkillThroughTime.py R package: https://github.com/glandfried/TrueSkillThroughTime.R  Full scientific documentation:
 English. Last version 2021-07-26 Español. Última versión 2021-07-26  TrueSkillThroughTime.jl None of the commonly used skill estimators, such as TrueSkill, Glicko and Item-Response Theory, correctly models the temporal aspect, which prevents having both good initial estimates and comparability between estimates separated in time and space.
TrueSkill Through Time corrects those biases by modeling the entire history of activities using a single Bayesian network.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>