<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Landfried</title>
    <link>https://glandfried.github.io/authors/admin/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Landfried</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://glandfried.github.io/authors/admin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Plurinational Bayesian Congress</title>
      <link>https://glandfried.github.io/post/cbp/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glandfried.github.io/post/cbp/</guid>
      <description>Intersubjective agreements in contexts of uncertainty</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bayesian inference, learning and evolution</title>
      <link>https://glandfried.github.io/talk/2022_03_icc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glandfried.github.io/talk/2022_03_icc/</guid>
      <description>TrueSkill Through Time (TTT) Reliable initial skill estimates and historical comparability The TTT model is the current state-of-the-art skill estimator in the video game industry: it provides reliable initial skill estimates and guarantees historical comparability. Published more than a decade ago, it was not available in the programming languages with the largest scientific communities. In this paper we offer the first pack- age for Julia , Python and R , an efficient algorithm that allows millions of observations to be analyzed using any low-end CPU.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiplicative processes as the general driver for the emergence of cooperation and specialization</title>
      <link>https://glandfried.github.io/publication/landfried-transitions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glandfried.github.io/publication/landfried-transitions/</guid>
      <description>To explain why major evolutionary transitions are so common in the history of life we need to find the causes that systematically generate the irreversible emergence of cooperation and specialization. For this purpose it is necessary to consider selection at both the individual and group level. The co-author of the concept of major evolutionary transitions (Szathmáry) recently proposed to analyze the evolution of populations subject to multilevel selection by means of Bayesian hierarchical models, making use of the isomorphism between evolutionary theory and Bayesian inference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The state-of-the-art skill model</title>
      <link>https://glandfried.github.io/post/skill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glandfried.github.io/post/skill/</guid>
      <description>Reliable initial skill estimates and historical comparability with Julia, Python and R</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TrueSkill Through Time. The full scientific documentation</title>
      <link>https://glandfried.github.io/publication/landfried2021-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glandfried.github.io/publication/landfried2021-learning/</guid>
      <description>Most estimators implemented for the video game industry cannot obtain reliable initial estimates nor guarantee comparability between distant estimates. TrueSkill Through Time solves all these problems by modeling the entire history of activities using a single Bayesian network. This algorithm requires a few iterations to converge, allowing millions of observations to be analyzed using any low-end computer.
To support the use of reliable learning estimators, we provide the first implementations of TrueSkill Through Time for Julia, Python and R.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empirical knowledge is life</title>
      <link>https://glandfried.github.io/post/empiricalknowledge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glandfried.github.io/post/empiricalknowledge/</guid>
      <description>The reciprocal coexistence of diversities</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Honest Beliefs</title>
      <link>https://glandfried.github.io/post/honestbeliefs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glandfried.github.io/post/honestbeliefs/</guid>
      <description>The source of validity for empirical knowledge</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TrueSkill Through Time. The Julia, Python and R packages</title>
      <link>https://glandfried.github.io/publication/landfried2020-ttt/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glandfried.github.io/publication/landfried2020-ttt/</guid>
      <description>Packages:
Julia Package: https://github.com/glandfried/TrueSkillThroughTime.jl Python Package: https://github.com/glandfried/TrueSkillThroughTime.py R package: https://github.com/glandfried/TrueSkillThroughTime.R  Full scientific documentation:
English. Last version 2021-07-26 Español. Última versión 2021-07-26  TrueSkillThroughTime.jl None of the commonly used skill estimators, such as TrueSkill, Glicko and Item-Response Theory, correctly models the temporal aspect, which prevents having both good initial estimates and comparability between estimates separated in time and space.
TrueSkill Through Time corrects those biases by modeling the entire history of activities using a single Bayesian network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homo ergodicus</title>
      <link>https://glandfried.github.io/post/homoergodicus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glandfried.github.io/post/homoergodicus/</guid>
      <description>The ergodicity problem in evolutionary theory</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faithfulness-boost effect</title>
      <link>https://glandfried.github.io/publication/landfried2019-faithfulness/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glandfried.github.io/publication/landfried2019-faithfulness/</guid>
      <description>Playing as a team with same partners enable us to acquire individual skills that would hardly be achieved by playing alone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TrueSkill, Technical Report</title>
      <link>https://glandfried.github.io/publication/landfried2019-trueskill/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://glandfried.github.io/publication/landfried2019-trueskill/</guid>
      <description>The first skill estimator was developed by Arpad Elo, adopted by the World Chess Federations around 1970. TrueSkill is just the bayesian multiplayer version of Elo model, published by Microsoft in 2007. In this technical report I derive, step by step, the analytical solution of the model.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
